+49 157-83632890 Rychartweg 5, 89075 Ulm Germany niebel.math@gmail.com

Lukas Niebel

PhD Student at Ulm University

Personal Website uni-ulm.de/index.php?id=97773

I am a third-year PhD student at Ulm University. My research concerns the regularity theory of kinetic partial differential equations, including the fractional Kolmogorov equation. I am interested in studying the L^p -regularity theory of solutions and understanding a priori estimates for weak solutions. The goal is to apply these results to quasilinear kinetic partial differential equations. Preprints of all publications are available on arXiv.

EDUCATION

EDUCATION	
PhD student Ulm University	2019 — 2022
 Working title: Analytic aspects of kinetic partial differential equations Advisor: Prof. Dr. Rico Zacher 	
Master of Science in Mathematics Ulm University	2018 — 2019
 Thesis: Kolmogorov equations - Well-Posedness, regularity, asymptotics and Harnack inequalities Grade: 1.0 with distinction, honors for best graduation 	
Bachelor of Science in Mathematics Ulm University	2014 — 2018
 Thesis: Long-time behavior of Markov chains by discrete functional inequalities and entropic Ricci curvature Grade: 1.1 with distinction, honors for best graduation 	
Abitur, Joachim-Hahn-Gymnasium Blaubeuren Junior studies in mathematics, Fernuniversität Hagen and PfH Göttingen	2014 2013 — 2014
Publications	
Kinetic maximal L^p -regularity with temporal weights and application to quasilinear kinetic diffusion equations Journal of Differential Equations, link to the article.	2022
Kinetic maximal $L^p_\mu(L^p)$ -regularity for the fractional Kolmogorov equation with variable density Nonlinear Analysis, link to the article. Kinetic maximal L^2 -regularity for the (fractional) Kolmogorov equation Journal of Evolution Equations, link to the article.	2022
AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS	
Master Graduation Award "Absolventenpreis M.Sc. Mathematik Uni Ulm 2020" Graduate scholarship granted by the State of Baden-Wuerttemberg, Germany (Grant Number 1902 LGFG-E) Bachelor Graduation Award "Absolventenpreis B.Sc. Mathematik Uni Ulm 2018" Ferry Porsche Award	2022 2019 — 2022 2018 2014
Working Experience	
Working student Daimler AG Research & Development	2015 — 2019 Ulm, Germany
Scientific assistant Ulm University	2017 — 2019 <i>Ulm, Germany</i>
Teaching (see separate section).Organization of the Trainingscamp. A yearly event for first-year students to refresh their mathematical skills.	
Student assistant Ulm University	2015 — 2017 <i>Ulm, Germany</i>
Teaching (see separate section).	
Volunteer Work	
Elected member in the council of PhD students at Ulm University Elected member of the faculty council for Mathematics and Economic Sciences of Ulm University Academic Student Council Mathematics	2020 — 2022 2020 — 2022 2017 — 2019

+49 157-83632890 Rychartweg 5, 89075 Ulm Germany niebel.math@gmail.com

Communication

Lukas Niebel

PhD Student at Ulm University

Personal Website uni-ulm.de/index.php?id=97773

TEACHING EXPERIENCE	CE	
Teaching assistant, Uni	nical Systems, Elements of Functional analysis	2020 — 2022 2017 — 2019 2015 — 2017
OTHER SCIENTIFIC AC	CTIVITIES	
Organization of a mini-v Organization of a projec Visiting researcher, Écol	seminar "Mathematisches Kolloquium" at Ulm University workshop for PhD students in mathematics at Ulm University ct for the Workshop of the 25th ISem on "Spectral theory for Operators and Semigroups" le normale supérieure Paris, one week n school "COLLAB – Collaboratory for Global Sustainability 2021"	2020 — 2022 2022 2022 2021 2021
TALKS AND POSTERS		
Talk — Nonlinear Evolut Talk — Oberseminar Ana	alysis of kinetic equations, Isaac Newton Insitute Cambridge tion Equations and Approximations, Essen alysis, Ulm on Analysis and Applied Mathematics, Münster	2022 2021 2021 2021
ATTENDED CONFEREI	NCES	
Kinetic Theory: old and Frontiers in analysis of k Deep Learning and part Recent advances in Grad Kinetic Equations: from Winterschool on Analys PDE/Probability Interac Parabolic Evolution Equ	y Between Probability and Kinetic Theory, Edinburgh new tutorial, INI Cambridge (virtual) kinetic equations, INI Cambridge (virtual) ial differential equations, INI Cambridge (virtual) dient Flows, Kinetic Theory, and Reaction-Diffusion Equations, Wien (virtual) Modeling Computation to Analysis, CIRM Marseille (virtual) is and Applied Mathematics, Münster (virtual) tions: Particle Systems, Hyperbolic Conservation Laws, CIRM Marseille sations, Harmonic Analysis And Spectral Theory, Bad Herrenalb s in Fluids, Kinetic Equations and Probability, CIRM Marseille	2022 2022 2022 2022 2021 2021 2021 2021
SKILLS IT Skills	C++, Excel (VBA), Java, धा <u>E</u> X, Mathematica, Matlab, R	
	Advanced understanding of software and hardware	

German (native speaker), English (C1), French (B1)